<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<technical-decisions  xmlns:h="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" 
		      xmlns="https://niap-ccevs.org/cc/v1">
  <decision id='365' date="2018.10.12"
	    url="https://www.niap-ccevs.org/Documents_and_Guidance/view_td.cfm?td_id=375">
    <Issue_Description> Something </Issue_Description>
    <Resolution> Something Else </Resolution>
    <Justification> My <h:p>Justification</h:p></Justification>
    <Other_References>Something</Other_References>
  <!-- 
	 Selections with IDs *MUST* have the same IDs as those in the original PP.
    -->
    <Protection_Profiles>
      <Protection_Profile max-inclusive="4.2" name="General Purpose Operating System">
	<replace>
          <f-element id="FCS_CKM_EXT.4.1">
	    <title>
The OS shall destroy cryptographic keys and key material in accordance with a specified cryptographic key destruction method 
              <selectables>
		<selectable>For volatile memory, the destruction shall be executed by a 
		<selectables>
		  <selectable>single overwrite consisting of <selectables>
		      <selectable>a pseudo-random pattern using the TSF's RBG</selectable>
		      <selectable>zeroes</selectable>
		      <selectable>ones</selectable>
		      <selectable>a new value of a key</selectable>
		      <selectable><assignable> any value that does not contain any CSP</assignable></selectable></selectables></selectable>
		  <selectable>removal of power to the memory</selectable>
		  <selectable>destruction of reference to the key directly followed by a request for garbage collection</selectable>
		</selectables></selectable>
		<selectable>For non-volatile memory that consists of 
		<selectables>
		  <selectable>destruction of all key encrypting keys protecting the target key according to FCS_CKM_EXT.4.1, where none of the KEKs protecting the target key are derived</selectable>
		  <selectable>the invocation of an interface provided by the underlying platform that <selectables>
		    <selectable>logically addresses the storage location of the key and performs a <selectables>
			<selectable>single</selectable>
			<selectable><assignable>ST author defined multi-pass</assignable></selectable>
		      </selectables>
overwrite consisting of 
                      <selectables>
			<selectable>zeroes</selectable><selectable>ones</selectable>
			<selectable>pseudo-random pattern</selectable>
			<selectable>a new value of a key of the same size</selectable>
			<selectable><assignable>any value that does not contain any CSP</assignable></selectable>
		      </selectables></selectable>
		    <selectable>instructs the underlying platform to destroy the abstraction that represents the key</selectable>
		  </selectables></selectable>
	      </selectables></selectable>
	      </selectables>
	      .
	    </title>
	    <note role="application">
	      <h:p>
The interface referenced in the requirement could take different forms, the most likely of which is an application programming interface to an OS kernel. There may be various levels of abstraction visible. For instance, in a given implementation that overwrites a key stored in non-volatile memory, selection a, the application may have access to the file system details and may be able to logically address specific memory locations. In another implementation that instructions the underlying platform to destroy the representation of a key stored in non-volatile memory, the application may simply have a handle to a resource and can only ask the platform to delete the resource, as may be the case with a platforms secure key store. The latter implementation should only be used for the most restricted access. The level of detail to which the TOE has access will be reflected in the TSS section of the ST.
	      </h:p>
	      <h:p>
Several selections allow assignment of a 'value that does not contain any CSP'. This means that the TOE uses some other specified data not drawn from a source that may contain key material or reveal information about key material, and not being any of the particular values listed as other selection options. The point of the phrase 'does not contain any CSP' is to ensure that the overwritten data is carefully selected, and not taken from a general 'pool' that might contain current or residual data that itself requires confidentiality protection.
	      </h:p>

	      <h:p>
For the selection "destruction of all key encrypting keys protecting target key according to FCS_CKM_EXT.4.1, where none of the KEKs protecting the target key are derived", a key can be considered destroyed by destroying the key that protects the key. If a key is wrapped or encrypted it is not necessary to "overwrite" that key, overwriting the key that is used to wrap or encrypt the key used to encrypt/decrypt data, using the appropriate method for the memory type involved, will suffice. For example, if a product uses a Key Encryption Key (KEK) to encrypt a Data Encryption Key (DEK), destroying the KEK using one of the methods in FCS_CKM_EXT.4 is sufficient, since the DEK would no longer be usable (of course, presumes the DEK is still encrypted and the KEK cannot be recovered or re-derived.).
	      </h:p>
	    </note>

	    <aactivity>
	      <TSS>
		This activity wasn't valid.
	      </TSS>
              </aactivity>
	  </f-element>
	</replace>
      </Protection_Profile>
    </Protection_Profiles>
  </decision>
</technical-decisions>

